A Guide to the Carr-Cary Family Papers
University of Virginia Library
- James O. Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1818 Aug 2 (Box Box 1)
  [further discussions of the intention of James & Mary Carr to buy Carrsbrook, mentions the University of Virginia, "the good citizens of Charlottesville are on their heads about the University which is shortly to be located," which is believed to be fixed at the Central College; mentions James Minor and his efforts concerning the old mill road for his mother, Hetty, and the deliverance of his overseer's wife of twins (the last year she had triplets)]
- Hetty Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1818 Aug 9 (Box Box 1)
  [the girls are at Jefferson Randolph's, George is exchanging his house for a larger one, further discussions of the intention of James & Mary Carr to buy Carrsbrook, and her feeling that she must sell everything that cannot be transported by water to Baltimore]
- John A. Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1818 Aug 15 (Box Box 1)
  [during a trip to Winchester, describes his rescue of a gig stuck in the mud, his impression of the Alleghany Mountains, and includes a humorous and slightly risque story]
- Hetty Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1818 Oct 4 (Box Box 1)
  [the offer of Dabney Minor for Carrsbrook, the sale of the slaves Elizabeth and Betsy to R.G. Martin, who offers the same price to Maria for Jenny, asks George to make application so she can transport her slaves, Phil, Betty, Peter, Robert and his wife, Mary, and their two children, Esther and her man]
- Hetty Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1818 Oct 15 (Box Box 1)
  [provides details of her sale of Carrsbrook to Dabney Minor, and the public sale on November 19th, of her slaves and other property]
- John A. Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1818 Oct 18 (Box Box 1)
  [writes from the ship U.S.S. Independence, being a midshipman in the U.S. Navy, and describes a fight he participated in at a theater in [Boston?]
- Hetty Carr to Dabney S. Carr, [1818] Oct 22 (Box Box 1)
  [discusses the results of the sale, and mentions getting a power of attorney for the sale of Ben's family, belonging to George]
- Hetty Carr to Dabney S. Carr, [1818] Oct 25 (Box Box 1)
  [discusses the sale of the family slaves, hoping to sell them to family or to neighbors if possible, the death of the slave named Phil, and the sale of her furniture and furnishings]
- Jane Hollins Randolph to Dabney S. Carr, [1818] Oct 28 (Box Box 1)
  [requests that Carr introduce Dr. Bramham into Baltimore society]
- Dabney Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1818 Oct 31 (Box Box 1)
  [has sent Dabney S. Carr's deed to lands near Clarksburg, [West] Virginia, with a gentleman to be recorded in the court of the newly formed Lewis County]
- George P. Stevenson to Dabney S. Carr, 1818 Nov 2 (Box Box 1)
  [business & moral instructions and the progress of the voyage to Havana]
- John Brand[egee] to George P. Stevenson, 1818 Nov 2 (Box Box 1)
  [discusses business]
- John A. Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1818 Nov 6 (Box Box 1)
  [witnesses the fire in the Boston Exchange Coffee House and the subsequent blaze in the Navy Yard, and two midshipmen tried for overstaying their leave on shore]
- Hetty Carr to Dabney S. Carr, [1818] Nov [10] (Box Box 1)
  [describes the sale of the family slaves, and makes arrangements about her furniture]
- Hetty Carr to George P. Stevenson, [1818?] Nov 10 (Box Box 1)
  [worries about the repayment of George's debts, James Carr's purchase of Ben's family, and the arrangements for the sale of the other slaves]
- John A. Carr to Dabney S. Carr, [1818] Nov 17 (Box Box 1)
  [describes more adventures of the midshipman life]
- Hetty Carr to Dabney S. Carr, [1818] Nov 26 (Box Box 1)
  [reports on the sale of slaves and furniture, Uncle Sam is to marry in a week and Martha and Dabney Minor are to marry]
- George P. Stevenson to Dabney S. Carr, 1818 Dec 2 (Box Box 1)
  [business instructions]
- James O. Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1818 Dec 7 (Box Box 1)
  [forwards one hundred dollars from his mother to Dabney Carr]
- John A. Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1818 Dec 8 (Box Box 1)
  [describes his life on the ship and adventures in swabbing the deck when the temperature was freezing]
- Hetty Carr to Dabney S. Carr, [1818] Dec 14 (Box Box 1)
  [arrangements to come to Baltimore and set up housekeeping with Eliza temporarily, and her concerns over whether her daughter-in-law is really willing for her to come]
- John A. Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1818 Dec 26 (Box Box 1)
  [has heard word of George Hollins and John Nicholas on board the Mediterranean, and mentions a brawl in the Boston theater]
- Hetty Carr to Dabney S. Carr & Others, [1818] Dec 28 (Box Box 1)
  [fears that Eliza is no longer interested in a joint housekeeping venture, mentions the marriage of Martha and Dabney Minor, and discusses business]
- Hetty Carr to Dabney S. Carr, [1818] (Box Box 1)
  [discusses business and gives advice]
- Eliza Stevenson to Dabney S. Carr, [1818?] (Box Box 1)
  [writes concerning a slave, Letty, and her concerns about sending her to Georgia to be among strangers or even Louisiana without her consent, despite her being brought home by a constable]
- Hetty Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1819 Jan 3 (Box Box 2)
  [complains that Maria seldom writes her, reports on the selling of her furniture, longs to see her children and her concerns about housekeeping in Baltimore]
- John A. Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1819 Jan 18 (Box Box 2)
  [describes his courting activities in Boston, wonders about the absence of letters from his father, and has not received his orders to The Hornet]
- Hetty Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1819 Jan 24 (Box Box 2)
  [discusses a check, family affairs, and furniture]
- John A. Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1819 Jan 27 (Box Box 2)
  [discusses the merits of Boston girls and Virginia girls, parties, his anger at his father for not writing, and his hopes to sail aboard The Hornet]
- Hetty Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1819 Jan 31 (Box Box 2)
  [discusses her proposed trip to Baltimore and other business]
- Hetty Carr to Dabney S. Carr, [1819 Jan] (Box Box 2)
  [hopes to come to Baltimore in March if the roads are not too bad and discusses family affairs]
- Hetty Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1819 Feb 5 (Box Box 2)
  [asks if he has gotten permission for her to bring her slaves to Baltimore, trouble over the slave Elizabeth because Samuel Carr neglected to apply to the General Assembly for leave to keep her in Virginia, describes the attack of Charles L. Bankhead upon Jefferson Randolph at court with a knife on February 1st, and weakened by his wounds, Randolph remained at the home of Alexander Garrett for awhile until he could be moved; remarks that "poor Mr. Jefferson was dreadfully agitated when he saw him first"]
- James O. Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1819 Feb 7 (Box Box 2)
  [shares his pride that Virginia has established and endowed the University of Virginia at the location of Central College which will have about 300 students as estimated by Thomas Jefferson]
- John A. Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1819 Feb 8 (Box Box 2)
  [glad that Dabney has deferred his plan to marry [Mary Taylor?] until next fall, and the possibility that he may sail on The Columbian]
- Hetty Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1819 Feb 9 (Box Box 2)
  [asks Dabney to make final arrangements with Mr. Montgomery to bring her and family to Baltimore, asks concerning her letters and what they said about her bargain with Dabney Minor for the land, which is in dispute, and reports on Jefferson Randolph's condition]
- John A. Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1819 Feb 22 (Box Box 2)
  [remarks concerning the actions of Charles L. Bankhead, and wishes his friend would visit Monticello and remember John Carr to all the folks there, especially to Mrs. Randolph]
- M. Gilmer to Mrs. Virginia Cary, 1819 Mar 11 (Box Box 2)
  [mentions that Jefferson Randolph is almost restored to health, mentions Dabney Carr, Major Divers, Mrs. Coleman, and Ann Bankhead moving out of the county]
- Wilson J. Cary (1784-1823) to Wilson Miles Cary (1806-1877), 1819 Apr 20 (Box Box 2)
  [writes from Carysbrook to his son at the Staunton Academy, mentions General John Hartwell Cocke's willingness to send up his carryall for his son, John Hartwell Cocke (1804-1846) and Wilson, General Cocke believes that soon a grammar school will be established by Thomas Jefferson in Charlottesville, who has written to Dr. Cooper in Philadelphia about engaging a competent teacher, and neighborhood disasters as a result of fires, including the death of the foreman at Oakhill who had a tree fall on his head]
- Mary Randolph Harrison to Mrs. Virginia Cary, 1819 Apr 24 (Box Box 2)
  [mentions Jane Randolph, Virginia's sister, and her daughter Jane [Randolph] who recently had a baby and is still at home with her]
- M. Gilmer to Mrs. Virginia Cary, 1819 May 12 (Box Box 2)
  [describes a visit to the Peaks of Otter, the meeting of the Presbytery of Hanover, with sermons by Mr. Rice of Petersburg and Mr. Lyle of Prince Edward, and her experiences in gardening]
- John A. Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1819 May 16 (Box Box 2)
  [upset that no one has written for two months, has heard that Carrsbrook has burned, and describes his struggles with a runaway sailor in Boston]
- John A. Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1819 Jun 3 (Box Box 2)
  [discusses the girls of Boston and asks about family & friends]
- Tobias S. Collis to Dabney S. Carr, 1819 Jun 4 (Box Box 2)
  [continues to teach in Louisa County having refused an appointment to West Point, but may emigrate to Pensacola in the fall if he doesn't get married]
- Vincent Gray to Mr. McBlair - Copy, 1819 Jun 10 (Box Box 2)
  [announcing the death of George P. Stevenson in Havana, Cuba, of a fever]
- James O. Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1819 Jun 11 (Box Box 2)
  [remarks on the scarcity of money and its effects on the economy, the disadvantages of being a merchant, plans for the wagon with the servants to leave Charlottesville tomorrow, and asks if a Miss Campbell can accompany Hetty Carr for safety]
- John A. Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1819 Jun 17 & Jun 24 (Box Box 2)
  [his work as a commodore's aid, sorry to hear Hetty is leaving Baltimore so soon, language of Yankee ladies, and the wounding of his friend]
- John A. Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1819 Jun 28 (Box Box 2)
  [transferred to The Constellation]
- Dabney Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1819 Jul 2 (Box Box 2)
  [concerning his land in Lewis County, [West] Virginia]
- James O. Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1819 Jul 5 (Box Box 2)
  [concerning the death of Dabney's brother, George P. Stevenson, and his land in Lewis County, [West] Virginia]
- John H. Eustace to Mrs. Hetty Carr, 1819 Jul 5 (Box Box 2)
  [sends $120.00 at the request of James O. Carr]
- John A. Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1819 Jul 5 (Box Box 2)
  [concerning the death of Dabney's brother, George P. Stevenson, and advice about a new vocation]
- Dabney Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1819 Jul 13 (Box Box 2)
  [concerning the death of Dabney's brother, George P. Stevenson, his land in Lewis County, and asks about the plans of the family]
- Dabney Minor to Dabney S. Carr, 1819 Jul 20 (Box Box 2)
  [concerning the death of Dabney's brother, George P. Stevenson, his land in Lewis County, Dabney Terrell, and asks about the plans of the family]
- Dabney Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1819 Jul 23 (Box Box 2)
  [concerning his land in Lewis County, [West] Virginia, and an offer to read law in his own office]
- James O. Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1819 Jul 24 (Box Box 2)
  [times are very hard, has no overseer at present, reports on the lack of progress of Central College, the notes of the North Carolina banks are refused, saw his friend Jack Carr who left them yesterday, and advises Dabney to quit the mercantile business]
- Mary Randolph Harrison to Mrs. Virginia Cary, 1819 Aug 7 (Box Box 2)
  [both her husband and son-in-law, William, have been unwell, William, who has been at the Amelia Springs, will soon go to the Buckingham County Quarterly Court, accompanied by Jane to the home of Charles Irving, and asks if Virginia's daughter, Jane, can come to the dancing school with her children]
- Dabney Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1819 Sep 15 (Box Box 2)
  [makes arrangements for Dabney to take a position reading law in his office]
- Mary Jane Terrell to Mrs. Virginia Cary, 1819 Dec 17 (Box Box 2)
  [mentions the visit of Martha Jefferson Randolph and Ellen Randolph to Virginia, and discusses the misunderstanding over her comments concerning Mary Campbell, sister of Sally Peachy, to Lelia Barraud; someone has included genealogical notes]
- George P. Stevenson to Dabney S. Carr, [1819?] (Box Box 2)
  [business and moral instruction]
- Wilson J. Cary (1784-1823) to Virginia Cary (Incomplete), 1821 Dec 25 (Box Box 2)
  [instructions and plans for the education of their son, Wilson M. Cary, at the school of Mr. Maury, and refers to the unpleasant dispute between the governor, Thomas Mann Randolph, and the council]
- Wilson J. Cary to Mrs. Virginia Cary, [1821 Dec] (Box Box 2)
  [lists various items he has purchased for Tom Whitlock to bring to her on his return trip, and recounts an account of an exhibition of rope walking at a height of forty feet by a Frenchman, Godeau, at the Eagle Tavern in Williamsburg]
- Wilson J. Cary to Mrs. Virginia Cary, [1822] Jan 9 (Box Box 2)
  [discusses the sale of several slaves including: Martha and three children to Mr. Hopkins of Goochland County, Polly and two children to Mr. Farrar of Fluvanna County, the need to sell Nancy or Priss, and the interest of T.C. Nelson in Billy, who is the husband of Virginia Cary's cook]
- Wilson J. Cary to Mrs. Virginia Cary, 1822 Jan 16 (Box Box 2)
  [enumerates the articles sent by him through General John Hartwell Cocke to his wife, describes his social life, especially a large party given by John Rutherford in Richmond, discusses schooling for his son, considering Hamden-Sydney if Mr. Maury's school disappoints, asks his wife to remove the wife and children of slave Julius from their household, instructs her to hire out any slaves she can, except for the boy Billy, and reports the rumor that her niece, Ellen, has Martin Van Buren of New York in her train as a suitor]
- Lelia Skipwith Tucker to Mrs. Rebecca Cary (1755-1823), 1822 Feb 11 (Box Box 2)
  [writes concerning the death of Rebecca's [granddaughter?], Anne Martha Cary (1813-1822), and other deaths in her neighborhood, Betsy Bassett, John Bracken, Mary Kennon Cocke Faulcon (1783-1822), and the illness of Mrs. Butler and John Blair Peachy]
- Wilson J. Cary to Mrs. Virginia Cary, 1822 Feb 11 (Box Box 2)
  [writes concerning the death of their daughter, Anne Martha Cary (1813-1822), her sister, Harriet Hackley, is still confined to her room, and mentions the visit of Henry Clay to the General Assembly and his speech]
- Wilson J. Cary to Mrs. Virginia Cary, 1822 Feb 15 (Box Box 2)
  [writes of a letter from his son, Wilson Miles, consoling him upon the death of Anne Martha Cary, his son's description of a drowning of a boy, Watson, from Charlottesville, who fell through the ice, and his plan to go down to Hampton, bring up slave Hannah and her family to sell in Richmond]
- J. S. Nicholas to Dabney S. Carr, 1822 Feb 16 (Box Box 2)
  [shares news of common friends and relatives in Virginia, and asks for a copy of the statutes of Maryland, where he hopes to join the bar]
- Wilson J. Cary to Mrs. Virginia Cary, 1822 Feb 21 (Box Box 2)
  [discusses religion, a concert by Mrs. French, a letter from his mother mentions the confinement of Mary Jane next month, the upcoming trip of William Newsum (1785-1828) westward, his friends, T.C. Nelson and Griffin Peachy both in town, the legacy of cousin Andrews, and is sending copies of
  Guy Mannering
  and
  The Pirate
  by Sir Walter Scott]
- Wilson J. Cary to Mrs. Virginia Cary, 1822 Feb 25 (Box Box 2)
  [river is high at Richmond, her sister Harriet, is much better, met [Joel Roberts] Poinsett, a member of Congress from South Carolina, saw Mrs. Randolph of Wilton, Miss Betsy Andrews, Miss Ballard, Robert & John Andrews, and Doctor Tazewell, plans to attend the last concert of Mrs. French, and mentions the marriage of Griffin Peachy's sister]
- John A. Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1822 Apr 23 (Box Box 2)
  [writes from the U.S. Constellation,a depressed letter from Valparaiso, Chile, about his prospects in the Navy, saw The Franklin in this port, and asks for correspondence]
- P. Harrison to Dabney S. Carr, 1822 Jun 20 (Box Box 2)
  [inquires about his progress in his study of law]
- John H. Eustace to Mrs. Hetty Carr, 1822 Jul 12 (Box Box 2)
  [encloses a draft]
- Dabney Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1822 Jul 22 (Box Box 2)
  [writes concerning a debt he owes for boots and his pleasure at hearing Dabney is reading law with Judge Dorsey]
- John H. Eustace to Dabney S. Carr, 1822 Jul 25 (Box Box 2)
  [defends the manner of his last payment to Hetty Carr]
- Dabney Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1822 Aug 2 (Box Box 2)
  [refers again to the debt for boots to Mr. Carson, warns of the dangers of procrastination, for which the Carrs are known, thanks him for a copy of
  The Fortunes of Nigel
  by Sir Walter Scott for which he offers a critique, advises him about studying with Judge Dorsey, and looking forward to seeing Jack, knowing their many letters to him have miscarried]
- Wilson J. Cary to Wilson Miles Cary, 1822 Nov 30 (Box Box 2)
  [writes concerning to his son at the Hampden Sydney College, the birth of a daughter, Louisa Hartwell, (who later died April 28, 1823), fires at the homes of Dr. Wills and Joshua Key, the marriage of Mary Elizabeth Randolph, daughter of Thomas Eston and Jane Cary Randolph, to Francis Eppes, son of John Wayles Eppes and Maria Jefferson, and work at the plantation]
- Dabney Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1822 Dec 8 (Box Box 2)
  [will continue to hire his slave Peter, and Doctor Grayson has told him that his nephew is about to take his place at the bar]
- Wilson J. Cary to Mrs. Virginia Cary, [1822?] Dec 9 (Box Box 2)
  [saw the last performance of [Junius Brutus?] Booth in
  King Richard
  , boarding at Mr. Poore's, a cabinet maker, discusses the election of governor, favoring James Pleasants, Jr., saw her sister Harriet Hackley whose husband was detained in New York on business, and the price of ordinary tobacco has fallen considerably]
- Wilson J. Cary to Mrs. Virginia Cary, 1822 Dec 12 (Box Box 2)
  [Thompson Payne is bringing a bundle to her from himself, which he describes, instruct the overseer to stem their long tobacco this year, asks about the progress on the mill, find out if Mr. Ashlin wishes to hire the slaves, Julius and Jack, and mentions the purchase of slave Polly by Mr. Hopkins of Goochland]
- Wilson J. Cary to Mrs. Virginia Cary, 1823 Jan 2 (Box Box 2)
  [Happy New Year wishes, bad market in Richmond for slaves, although they hire well, hard financial times, bad management of their property by the overseer, saw Colonel Thomas Mann Randolph who said that Thomas Jefferson was nearly recovered from his accident, and that Randolph was making great profits at Varina, and reports that Harriet Hackley was still physically very weak]
- Wilson J. Cary to Virginia Cary (Incomplete), 1823 Jan 6 (Box Box 2)
  [instructs her to get her sister at Monticello to try and clear up her misunderstanding with the Ashton family, pleased that she did not hire out the slaves to anyone who would use them ill, his debt obligates him to sell one of the slave girls, Priss or Nancy, Martha and her two youngest children sold to Mr. Farrar of Fluvanna, Polly and her children left at Cartersville with Dr. James, Sampson sold in the county, Elizabeth to be sold with her husband in Williamsburg by Dr. Peachy, and the marriage of Juliana Mayo to Dr. R.H. Cabell]
- Wilson J. Cary to Mrs. Virginia Cary, 1823 Jan 15 (Box Box 2)
  [describes articles he is sending and the money for Wilson]
- Wilson J. Cary to Wilson Miles Cary (Incomplete), 1823 Jan 16 (Box Box 2)
  [must economize due to the difficulty of the times, his dissatisfaction with Hampden Syndney if Wilson is only learning Greek, and an account of his slave sales]
- Wilson J. Cary to Virginia Cary, 1823 Feb 3 (Box Box 2)
  [writes concerning his slave William, the mill repairs, her sister, Harriet Hackley, his sister, Sally Newsum (1788-1841) who is still grieving over the loss of her child, Robert Starke Newsum, and the determination of William Newsum to take his father's claim for $16,000 before Congress]
- Wilson J. Cary to Mrs. Virginia Cary, 1823 Feb 17 (Box Box 2)
  [hopes the General Assembly session will soon end, and mentions the death of his "unfortunate Aunt [Sarah?] Fairfax]
- Wilson Miles Cary to Mrs. Virginia Cary, 1823 Oct 28 (Box Box 2)
  [attending the College of William and Mary, visits to Aunt Harriet Hackley and Aunt [Mary Munro] Peachy, his cousin, John Blair, has loaned him many of the books he needs, and describes classes]
- S. S. M. to John Spear Smith, 1824 Apr 26 (Box Box 2)
  [his statement for use in a suit regarding the intended dowry of the wife of John S. Smith]
- Wilson M. C. Fairfax to Mrs. Virginia Cary, 1824 Jun 27 (Box Box 2)
  [inquires about the payment of an annuity left by his grandfather, Wilson Miles Cary, in the hands of her late husband Wilson J. Cary (1784-1823), for Fairfax's mother]
- [T.L.N.?] to Dabney S. Carr, 1824 Sep 27 (Box Box 2)
  [an account of his difficult voyage as a sailor in the merchant service aboard the Quarantum, sailing from [New York?] with a load of flour for La Guaira, [presently Venzuela], the purchase of cocoa to sell in Tampico, Mexico, the Captain ashore at Havana, where the crew rebelled and attacked him physically demanding higher wages, until he quelled them]
- Wilson Miles Cary to Mrs. Virginia Cary, [1825] Jan (Box Box 2)
  [studying Greek in Charlottesville, boarding with Mr. Hatches, hears from the Monticello family every morning by Ben who comes to Mr. Hatches' school, the upcoming marriage of Ellen Randolph and Joseph Coolidge, and Thomas Jefferson's concerns for his faculty who have not yet arrived at the University of Virginia]
- Thomas Jefferson Randolph to Dabney S. Carr, 1825 May 10 (Box Box 2)
  [the mahogany plank arrived at Norfolk, was transferred to the deck of a steamboat bound for Richmond where it remains on the wharf, Carr's mother and the girls have arrived, and mentions interviews with booksellers from Philadelphia]
- Maria Jefferson Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1825 [Jun] 29 (Box Box 2)
  [describes the poor state of sister Ellen's health, seeing Doctors Gooch and Dunglison]
- Maria Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1825 Jul 2 (Box Box 2)
  [writes from Charlottesville, asks about Eliza, reports concerning the improvement in the health of their sister, Ellen]
- Hetty Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1825 Jul 10 (Box Box 2)
  [concern for Ellen's health, have been staying at Martha's for three weeks, concerns for the cost of their doctor bill, Maria in constant attendance upon her sister, and other business]
- Maria Jefferson Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1825 Jul 20 (Box Box 2)
  [plans to go to Tufton soon, Jane Margaret sick at Woodlands, and attended by Hetty Carr]
- Sidney Nicholas (1805-1886) to Dabney S. Carr, 1825 Jul 22 (Box Box 2)
  [asks him to secure iodine for her throat in Baltimore, his sister Ellen continues to improve, his mother and the baby are at James Carr's, the visit of Uncle Dabney, Aunt Betsy, and Nancy Carr]
- Hetty Carr to Dabney S. Carr, 1825 Aug 7 (Box Box 2)
  [Maria has been ill, Martha's son now with fever, asks why he does not write to his bride elect, which she advises him to do, her regret at not being able to give him a genteel wedding, and discusses the financial troubles of Thomas Jefferson Randolph, who will handle his grandfather's financial affairs]
- Hetty & Jane Margaret Carr to Dabney S. Carr, [1825 Aug] 13 (Box Box 2)